Phone 510.435.4794 E-mail <u>steveling@gmail.com</u> URL <u>http://www.slingonline.com</u>

Steve Shu-Chun Ling

Summary

UX designer and developer for responsive web and mobile with experiences in EdTech, B2B, and B2C small startups. Highly adaptive and cross functional in small groups/teams within all aspects of a product life cycle from wireframes to UX to design and development & QA to production.

Professional Experience

02/2014 - Present Berkeley Electronic Press Berkeley, CA

User Interface / Front-end Developer

- Hired to revamp next-generation scholarly publishing platform SelectedWorks
- Redesign the publishing platform from ground up by recreating interactions, wireframes, and storyboards that works for institutional librarians and administrators.
- Implement finalized and approved user interaction flows and interfaces within development codebase.
- Become the lead on resolving issues around all user interface issues using Django, Angular JS, Bootstrap, HTML5, and CSS.
- Living styleguide built for company-wide consumption to get consistent UI across all products of the company.
- Publishing platform now live for authors to showcase their work at http://works.bepress.com.

10/2013 - 12/2013 Handle

San Francisco, CA

UX Prototyper (Contract)

- Hired to translate mockup into code
- Adapted to learn Meteor Open Source platform and using Handlebars.js
- Applied strong HTML & CSS skills to make pixel perfect designs

11/2011 - 10/2013 CK-12 Foundation

Palo Alto, CA

Hands-on User Experience Lead

- Work with product managers and stakeholders to finalize every stage of the feature, storyboard, wireframe, and high definition mocks.
- Hands on with implementation of the approved mockups using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery and other advanced javascript libraries along with Python based templating engine Pylons and Jinja2.
- Hands on with mobile responsiveness of the CK-12 application across multiple mobile devices using HTML5, CSS3, and the Foundation Framework along with CSS media queries.
- Responsible for UI Styleguide and implementation of the UI Kit for company-wide consumption to get consistent look & feel across multiple company products and features
- Adaptive with different development and cross department processes such as agile or waterfall methodologies.
- Lead a team of 4 designers to upgrade the company's web application with relevant and current open source technology and frameworks.

http://www.ck12.org

05/2007 - Present CK-12 Foundation Palo Alto, CA

User Interface Engineer

- Hired to implement innovative and creative user interface for the advanced online application for authoring textbooks.
- Responsible the design of the logo and everything outbound/marekting related to the company.
- Responsible in creating mockups and storyboards in turn to implement the application with HTML, CSS and advanced javascript libraries, such as scriptaculous and prototype.
- Also engaged in hands-on efforts to implement structural setup of the application by using Django and ExtJs, and using GWT as our base structure.
- Designed and engaged in implementation efforts of the CK-12 iPad Application
- http://www.ck12.org

04/2006 - 05/2007 MeeVee, Inc Burlingame, CA

Web Developer

- Hired to spearhead major overhaul of the application website via the use of CSS and AJAX as well as complex XHTML.
- Successfully gained a deeper knowledge of CSS which in turn took the lead in all CSS issues and layout implementation issues.
- Spearheaded coordination and communication with product team and designers to smooth transition the storyboard to implementation process of the engineering group.
- Responsible for all syndication partner implementation which involves multiple efforts including layout mockup and implementation via MeeVee website standards
- Defined style and UI guidelines for partners to follow to ensure smooth implementation and minimal timeframe to launch.
- http://www.meevee.com

05/2004 – 04/2006 Mixonic, Inc San Francisco, CA

UI Designer and Developer

- Hired to re-implement the new CD Online Duplication website launched with the site with two other members of the team in a two month period.
- Without previous experience with STRUTS, successfully implemented the new online duplication site with the technology along with JSP and continuously maintaining and adding new functionality to the site.
- Hands-on with Java coding and Java developers to produce the best results to achieve UI capabilities to improve user experience.
- Understanding and implementing XML Document in Microsoft Word to expedite invoice and print job paper-works.
- Provide creative ideas, prototyped and implemented new products and online brochures for company sales and marketing efforts.
- Researched and implemented enhancement of company web site search engine ranking using technologies such as keywords and landing pages.
- Drive and became responsible for all user interface efforts from coordinating with printers of CD & DVD inserts to incorporating customer feedback into website.
- Understanding of printing process and coordinate with production team to provide smooth transition of CD & DVD label and insert printing from website.
- Adapted through 3 different cycles of development team member changes along with reporting to 3 different managers at the same time including the CEO himself.
- http://www.mixonic.com

02/2004 - 05/2004 SpikeSource, Inc Menlo Park, CA

Web Designer (Contractor)

- Piloted and prototyped several web projects for this new startup including their 1st iteration of their corporate website.
- Used PHP and Smarty Template Technology to implement prototypes of the corporate website.
- Worked closely with application engineers to understand functional needs to be translated into user interfaces.

http://www.spikesource.com

02/2003 – 02/2004 Pincity.com Los Angeles, CA

User Interface Designer/Web Team Lead

- Responsible for the development and implementation of the new Pincity.com website by providing expertise in HTML, CSS, and Javascript and producing intelligent, intuitive web technologies
- Introduced Cascading Style Sheet as a new method of implementing the new Pincity.com website – making the development process more efficient.
- Reorganized website directory structures and naming convention into a more manageable manner and set design and coding standards and guidelines.
- Provide creative ideas by working with Sales & Marketing and creating actual
 online advertisement and newsflash for Pincity.com products. Understanding the
 importance of integrating the company's advertising campaigns with the website.
- Promoted to Team Lead and managed a team of engineers to better development efficiencies and task management.
- Lead efforts in defining corporate web goals and designing strategies to meet these goals, including managing a development team and integrating a variety of inputs.
- Maintained consistency in development procedures and established/executed project time lines.
- Lead efforts and set new standards in automating customer service and feedback reports to produce sensible sales and marketing trends.
- http://www.pincity.com

09/1999 - 01/2003 Asera, Inc. Belmont, CA

User Interface Engineer

- Responsible for the design and prototyping of User Interfaces Look & Feel for all major versions of the Asera Product.
- Responsible for designing and prototyping of more than 20 different look and feels for product demos and proof of concepts involved in the Asera Pre-Sales, Sales, Professional Services, and Engineering efforts.
- Work closely with application engineers to define the guidelines required for application UI development and with deployment engineers to define usability, adaptability, and customization requirements.
- Work closely with product managers to come up with functional specs with storyboards, mockups, and prototypes.
- Responsible for the first versions of the Asera application UI Guidelines.
- Responsible for the development of storyboarding tool used at the beginning of the
 engineering development process. This tool enabled developers to construct their
 own storyboards, which helped to speed up the development process.
- Consulted with external customers regarding usability/user interface issues.
 Deployed and developed UI changes using Asera IDE necessary to meet customer needs. Involvement with customers such as BP, E2open, DSM, and Steel 24x7.
- Assisted in the development of the Sales Consultant Toolkit. This tool enabled Sales Consultants in the field to change Asera application's UI on a fly, saving the consultants time and effort to meet different customer needs.
- Member of the UI SWAT team for reviewing application storyboards. The group was responsible for the evaluation of the application on the consistency of Asera UI standards based on the Asera UI Guideline.
- Assisted the Asera Integrated Development Environment Tool Group using Visual Basic to come up with prototypes of the tool.
- Assisted the Asera Integrated Development Environment Tool Group in stream-lining the UI development of Asera applications for the application engineers by providing expertise in HTML and CSS.
- Wireless Markup Language proof of concept. Involved in the prototyping of Asera product in WML format. Provided UI support and help on the development of the prototype.

Education & Relevant Projects

1995 - 1999 Purdue University West Lafayette, IN Bachelor of Science, Psychology – Human Factors

- Relevant Web Design Work
 - o IE/PSY 577 course website (1998)
 - [http://psych.purdue.edu/~577ta/welcome.html]
 - o Department of Consumer Science (1999)
- Relevant Course Research
 - Human Factors Research (1996 1999) [Professor Robert Proctor]
 - Human Learning Lab (1998) [Professor lan Neath]

Awards & Recognitions

- Design Contest Winner for Powweb Web Hosting Company's user control center.
 - http://forum.powweb.com/showthread.php?t=29884

Computer Skills

- Hand-coding experience HTML, XML, XHTML, DHTML, PHP, JSP, CSS, Struts, Javascript, & WML
- Expert knowledge of HTML, XHTML, CSS, & CSS2
- Solid Understanding of cross-browser issues
- Design tools Adobe Photoshop, Adobe ImageReady, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Pagemaker, Macromedia Dreamweaver, Macromedia Fireworks, Microsoft FrontPage, also familiar with Macromedia Flash.
- Other tools: Visual Studio, Visual Basic, Eclipse
- Familiar with Microsoft Visual Studio .NET & Microsoft ASP .NET Web Matrix
- Familiar with JAVA, PERL, PHP
- PC, MAC OS & Linux Platform.

Languages

- Fluent in written and spoken English and Mandarin/Chinese.
- Extensive skills in written and spoken French.

References

- References available upon request.
- Portfolio online at http://www.slingonline.com/